João de Maredo Borges

Porto, Portugal



hello@jbbmb.com



linkedin.com/in/jbbmb



https://jbbmb.com

## Summary

Everyone around João knew he was meant to work with technology since he was born.

After High School, he started his Bachelor's in Computer Sciences, got involved in numerous freelance projects and began experimenting with different industry roles. Over the years, he worked with insightful teams using a range of tools and technologies.

Recently, he grew special attention to detail for Quality Control and Agile Processes, fell in love with UX and wants to learn more about SwiftUI and IAM.

One thing to remember about him is that he can make a mean gin and tonic.

## **Experience**



## Technical Support Team Lead

**BNP Paribas - Securities Services** 

Jan 2022 - Present (1 year 8 months)

João is responsible for coordinating the Portuguese Production Team maintaining, first Atlassian's Jira and now, NeoLink - one of many BP2S' International SWIFT Transactional Systems. We aim to continuously support and deliver a set of specialized banking capabilities to our customers and partners, enabling value in the form of real-time cloud services.

Skills: Incident Management, Hands-on Technical Leadership, IBM Cloud, ServiceNow, SailPoint, SharePoint, Jira, Java, PL/SQL, Active Directory



## t System & Network Administrator

Plásticos Bueso II

Jun 2019 - Present (4 years 3 months)

From online presence, to order processing and security updates, João helps to maintain all of the IT infrastructure required to run his family's plastics injection business.

Skills: Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), JavaScript, DNS Administration

# Quality Assurance Analyst

#### **FOURSOURCE**

Apr 2021 - Nov 2021 (8 months)

João took on the responsibility of joining this startup's first line of Quality Control. His role was to transform expected behavioral requirements into fully decomposed, materialized and testable Acceptance Criteria, that go on to be developed in Go and Angular.

Skills: Unified Modeling Language (UML), Cypress, Postman API, Software Quality, Microservices

## Product Manager

#### **FOURSOURCE**

Sep 2020 - Apr 2021 (8 months)

Bridging the gap between stakeholders' expectations and team commitment, João's purpose at FOURSOURCE was quite simple: to continue delivering an engaging, tailored experience inside the largest B2B sourcing platform for apparel and textiles.

Skills: Bug Tracking, Product Management, Agile Methodologies, Scrum, Kanban, Jira

#### Field Representative

Câmara Municipal do Porto

Nov 2019 - Dec 2019 (2 months)

The Shop in Porto initiative tries to bring customers and traditional businesses together in the digital era. João was tasked with providing key physical materials to store owners, walking them through the online experience and also got the opportunity to beta test the iOS app.

#### **Software Developer**

#### CPCIT4ALL

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019 (4 months)

João's mission at this HR-focused company was to help during a critical transition to newer, web-based technologies. He was tasked with refining and re-implementing existing components, using mostly ASP.NET and pure JavaScript, to be re-used at a later stage.

Skills: C#, JavaScript, ASP.NET, .NET Framework, Full-Stack Development

# Software Developer

#### Celfocus

Apr 2018 - Jul 2018 (4 months)

This challenge involved refactoring a Spring-based Java corporate social network into a platform that could retain acquired skills by staff and match them to a new project, given its technical requirements.

Skills: Java, Spring MVC, Full-Stack Development

# Event Promoter

SLIDE IN Travel Apr 2015 - Mar 2016 (1 year)

# Fabric Worker

Plásticos Bueso II Jun 2013 - Jul 2013 (2 months)

## **Education**

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Sciences 2015 - Present

# Externato Ribadouro

High School Diploma, Sciences and Technology 2012 - 2015

## **Licenses & Certifications**

**Certificate of C2 Proficiency in English** - Cambridge University Press & Assessment English

Credential ID: A4565478

### **Skills**

Git • Maven • jQuery • Representational State Transfer (REST) • Final Cut Pro • Adobe Photoshop • WordPress • macOS • General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) • Public Speaking

#### **Honors & Awards**

1st ever "Cherry Pick Porto" Staff - NEI-ISEP
Jun 2016